

- **1** 08015665499
- ✓ y4yasertalha@gmail.com
- KIADB Industrial Area, Bengalore
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/s yed-yaser-mohasin-197132174/

SKILLS

- React.js
- Node.js
- Postgresql
- Solidity
- Ether.js
- Hardhat

SELF-INITIATED PROJECTS

<u>apirobo.live</u>

<u>websmsbot.netlify.com</u>

SYED YASER MOHASIN

SENIOR PRODUCT ENGINEER

I am a Front-End developer with four years of experience in the software industry. I am proficient in the latest development tools and techniques and am able to effectively manage independent projects and also collaborate effectively as part of a team.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR PRODUCT ENGINEER

LTIMindtree

2022 - present

- Remained knowledgeable in new standards, technologies, and trends in Reactjs website development.
- Worked to meet client deadlines.
- Provided effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications.
- Continually reinforce industry best practices.
- Effectively multi tasked and worked well with internal and external teams.
- Created detail technical and user documentation.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

3K Technologies

2021 - 2022

 Successfully implemented a complex, data-heavy web application using React, improving performance and user experience for millions of users.

EDUCATION

SECONDARY SCHOOL

Gov Higher Sceondary School

2011 - 2012

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY

Anna University

2012 - 2018

LANGUAGE

English

Tamil

Hindi

- Created and maintained a common Redux state and maintained api flow through Redux-saga.
- Implemented the application's performance and maintanability through current coding techniques like hooks etc.
- Integrated backend api's, made sure api's are efficiently used through out the app.

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

Mobigraph Solutions India Private Limited Mar 2020 - Dec 2020

- Implemented a cross-platform mobile application using React Native, improving the efficiency of code by utilizing hooks and integrating 3rd party libraries.
- Developed and maintained a set of reusable, welldocumented UI components that were used across multiple projects, saving time and effort for the development team.
- Improved the performance of a mobile application by optimizing React Native components and implementing techniques such as code-splitting and lazy loading.
- Gave end-to-end developement Support till Releasing the application in playstore

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Thalir Technology Solutions 2019 - 2020

- Developed UI components as per the Design Requirement with HTML and CSS.
- Quickly adopted to React library and started contributing React functionality.
- Wrote complex Logic in javascript to meet the Requirement.
- Improved the performance of a React web application by using modern is functionalities and avoiding loops.
- Collaborated with designers and product managers to iterate on the design and user experience, resulting in increased user engagement.